<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-03-31T11:47:29+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Centre for Networked Intelligence</title><subtitle>&apos;The Centre for Networked Intelligence, under the division of EECS and RBCCPS, IISc, aims to develop next generation networking methodologies and concept solutions that can derive knowledge from evolved networks of the future.&apos; </subtitle><entry><title type="html">PhD Thesis Oral Defence: Minimizing latency in data acquisition, distributed processing, storage, and retrieval</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/rooji_defense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhD Thesis Oral Defence: Minimizing latency in data acquisition, distributed processing, storage, and retrieval"/><published>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/Rooji%20Defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/rooji_defense/"><![CDATA[ <p><img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/assets/img/people/phd/Rooji.jpg" width="100"/></p> <p>Rooji Jinan, CNI Fellow during 2019-20 and 2021-22, will defend her thesis on March 1, 2023 (Wednesday) at 10 am.</p> <p><strong>Venue: RBCCPS Board Room</strong> (in-person event).</p> <h3 id="thesis-abstract">Thesis abstract</h3> <p>We study minimization of file access delays in distributed storage systems. We consider the setting of a distributed storage system where a single file is subdivided into smaller fragments of same size which are then replicated with a common replication factor across servers of identical cache size. An incoming file download request is sent to all the servers, and the download is completed whenever the request gathers all the fragments. At each server, we are interested in determining the set of fragments to be stored, and the sequence in which fragments should be accessed, such that the mean file download time for a request is minimized. We model the fragment download time as an exponential random variable independent and identically distributed for all fragments across all servers and show that the mean file download time can be lower bounded in terms of the expected number of useful servers summed over all distinct fragment downloads. We study deterministic storage schemes that attempt to maximize the number of useful servers. We show that finding the optimal sequence of accessing the fragments is a Markov decision problem, whose complexity grows exponentially with the number of fragments. We propose heuristic algorithms that determine the sequence of access to the fragments which are empirically shown to perform well.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="defense"/><category term="PhD"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CNI Hackathon 2022 concludes: winners announced</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/hackathon22_concludes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNI Hackathon 2022 concludes: winners announced"/><published>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/CNI_Hackathon_2022_concludes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/hackathon22_concludes/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Another successful CNI hackathon has concluded. Congratulations to the winners!</strong></p> <p>The CNI Hackathon 2022 sought and attracted participation from undergraduate and master’s degree students from Indian institutes. The participants were allowed to form teams of at most two individuals to make their submissions. The event consisted of a Data Science challenge and an AI challenge. The data science challenge was related to a Bengaluru Metropolitan Transport Corporation (BMTC) dataset. The participants had to use the dataset and create a model to estimate the travel time between different source-destination pairs. In the AI Challenge, the participants had to create a bot to play a two-player board game.</p> <h3 id="participation">Participation</h3> <p>The Hackathon attracted participants from institutes across India, with more than 1150 registrations. In the data science challenge, 15 teams made valid submissions. On the other hand, in the AI challenge, we saw higher participation, with 74 teams making valid submissions. Overall, these teams comprise more than 150 individuals from some of the well-known institutes in India.</p> <h3 id="evaluation-strategy">Evaluation Strategy</h3> <ul> <li>Data Science Challenge: The models were evaluated based on their performance on a test dataset. The better models had lower L1 errors in the travel time predictions.</li> <li>AI Challenge: The models were evaluated based on their performance on a test dataset. The better models had lower L1 errors in the travel time predictions.</li> <li>Jury presentation: The models were evaluated based on their performance on a test dataset. The better models had lower L1 errors in the travel time predictions.</li> </ul> <p>The jury comprised experts from industry and IISc, and final jusy presentations were held on January 19, 2023.</p> <p><img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/images/posts/hackathon2022_winners.png" alt=""/></p> <p>Winners are awarded prizes worth up to ₹ 1.75 lakhs per track, sponsored by <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en_in/about/csr.html">Cisco CSR</a>.</p> <p><strong>Thank you, Cisco, for sponsoring and championing the event! We also thank Bengaluru Metropolitan Transport Corporation (BMTC) for sharing the data that helped conduct the Data Science Challenge. Further, we thank the department of ECE, RBCCPS, CiSTUP, and Thingcubator NASSCOM Foundation for all their support.</strong></p> <p>For further details, please visit <a href="https://cnihackathon.in">https://cnihackathon.in</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another successful CNI hackathon has concluded. Congratulations to the winners!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CNI Hackathon 2022: Data Science and AI Challenges</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/cni-hackathon-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNI Hackathon 2022: Data Science and AI Challenges"/><published>2022-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/CNI_Hackathon_2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/cni-hackathon-2022/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>The 2022 edition of CNI Hackathon is here!</em></strong></p> <p>The Centre for Networked Intelligence (CNI) at the Indian Institute of Science (IISc), Bengaluru, invites Indian students to participate in CNI Hackathon 2022.</p> <p><img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/images/posts/hackathon2022_poster.png" alt=""/></p> <p>The hackathon has two tracks: Data Science Challenge and an AI Challenge. The data science task involves a bus fleet dataset obtained from BMTC (Bengaluru Metropolitan Transport Corporation). The AI challenge consists of building a bot that competes with another bot to conquer more cells (area) in a grid.</p> <p>Winners are eligible for prizes worth up to ₹ 1.75 lakhs per track, sponsored by <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en_in/about/csr.html">Cisco CSR</a>.</p> <p>For further details and registration, please visit <a href="https://cnihackathon.in">https://cnihackathon.in</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="events"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2022 edition of CNI Hackathon is here!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MTech (Res) Defense: Empirical study of traffic generation for data centre networks</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/bidhov_defense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MTech (Res) Defense: Empirical study of traffic generation for data centre networks"/><published>2022-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/Bidhov_defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/bidhov_defense/"><![CDATA[<p>A member of CNI team, Bidhov Bizar, will be defending his MTech (Research) thesis on October 28, 2022 at 10 am.</p> <p><strong>Venue: Room 1.06, ECE Department</strong> (in-person event).</p> <h3 id="thesis-abstract">Thesis abstract</h3> <p>Data centre networks form the backbone for modern Internet giants like Google, Facebook, Microsoft, and Amazon. Such networks consist of a layer of large number of storage and compute servers connected through two or three layers of switches. Depending on the target application, data centre networks can be designed to have the desired properties. In many cases, the service providers must meet service level agreements for target applications. These agreements include the provision for redundant paths, the acceptable level of encryption, and the acceptable latency. The design choices available at the onset is architecture selection. Once the architecture is fixed, the available design choices include path selection, admission control, and encryption levels.</p> <p>The performance of a data centre network depends critically on the traffic profile in the network. Unfortunately, most of the traffic data is proprietary and seldom available to academic researchers. The industry benchmark performance tests are performed for periodic and burst packet traffic transmission. These are not representative of real traffic in the data centre networks. In this work, we focus on the problem of representative load generation for the empirical studies of data centre networks through emulation and simulation.</p> <p>The main characteristic of a traffic are the inter-arrival time of flows for each source destination pair, their corresponding lifetimes, and their bandwidths. In this thesis, we study the type of traffic required and the way to generate realistic traffic that is rich enough to test the data centre networks. We propose an open-source simulation framework to understand the type of traffic required and an open-source realistic traffic generator which plays real life traffic traces, which would help us understand the response of the data centre networks in production. The traffic generator contains a library of traffic patterns which can be used for the load testing with certain traits which is obtained from traffic archive group like MAWI, NLANR, WIDE etc.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="defense"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A member of CNI team, Bidhov Bizar, will be defending his MTech (Research) thesis on October 28, 2022 at 10 am.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CNI MTech Fellowship (2022-23)</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/masters-fellowship-2022-23/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNI MTech Fellowship (2022-23)"/><published>2022-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/Masters_Fellowship_2022-23</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/masters-fellowship-2022-23/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="call-for-applications-cni-mtech-fellowship-2022-23">Call for applications: CNI MTech Fellowship (2022-23)</h2> <p>Applications are invited for a Research Fellowship Programme under the Centre for Networked Intelligence (a Cisco CSR Initiative). The fellowship will be for the duration of 01 August 2022 to 30 June 2023.</p> <h3 id="eligibility">Eligibility:</h3> <p>Full-time EECS and RBCCPS second-year MTech students (course MTech as well as MTech-research, admitted through the regular admission process), not granted another externally sponsored fellowship, are eligible to apply.</p> <p>The evaluation committee will look at the applicant’s academic profile, proposed contributions to CNI activities, and the relevance of the proposed research to the Centre’s objective of showcasing innovative applications or theories of networked intelligence. Higher relevance will be assigned to proposed work in the current CNI project topics:</p> <ul> <li>Data center networks</li> <li>Data-driven decision frameworks for public health</li> <li>Deterministic networks and programmable data plane</li> <li>Industrial control systems</li> <li>Wi-Fi optimisation and network slicing</li> </ul> <h3 id="monthly-fellowship-support">Monthly fellowship support:</h3> <p>The CNI fellows will be selected by the evaluation committee, and the CNI scholarship will be in lieu of the MoE scholarship. Exact amount will be indicated at the time of award, and a selected few fellows will receive a slightly higher monthly remuneration.</p> <h3 id="additional-benefits">Additional benefits:</h3> <p>CNI also offers financial support for research publications and conference travel (up to Rs 1 lakh) subject to availability of funds.</p> <p>Additional honorarium will be paid to the fellows assisting in conducting CNI events. CNI fellows are expected to actively participate in CNI events and contribute towards CNI activities during the year.</p> <h3 id="application-process">Application process:</h3> <p>The following information should be included in the fellowship application:</p> <ol> <li>Covering letter indicating how your work relates to networked intelligence systems and the Centre’s areas of interest. Please indicate how you propose to contribute to CNI activities such as network seminar series organisation or online course modules (mention the course topics).</li> <li>Full academic résumé including marks/grades in Bachelors, other degrees, years of graduation, honours and awards, publications, work experience, etc.</li> <li>IISc course transcript.</li> <li>A one-page write-up on your research area — include a short review, broad problem statement, proposed scope, and focus. Please include any results already obtained and the papers published.</li> </ol> <p>The application <strong>email</strong> with a single PDF document as attachment (size at most 10 MB) <em>needs to be forwarded by adviser</em> and should reach contact.cni@iisc.ac.in <strong>on or before <del>16-Aug-2022</del> 21-Aug-2022 (IST)</strong>.</p> <p>More details on past CNI fellowships are at <a href="https://cni.iisc.ac.in">https://cni.iisc.ac.in</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for applications: CNI MTech Fellowship (2022-23)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CNI Ph.D. Fellowship (2022-23)</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/phd-fellowship-2022-23/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNI Ph.D. Fellowship (2022-23)"/><published>2022-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/PhD_Fellowship_2022-23</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/phd-fellowship-2022-23/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="call-for-applications-cni-phd-fellowship-2022-23">Call for applications: CNI PhD Fellowship (2022-23)</h2> <p>Applications are invited from the PhD students in the Division of EECS and the RBCCPS for a Research Fellowship Programme under the Centre for Networked Intelligence (a Cisco CSR Initiative). The fellowship will be for the duration of 01 August 2022 to 31 July 2023 or completion of PhD, whichever is earlier.</p> <h3 id="eligibility">Eligibility:</h3> <p>Full-time EECS and RBCCPS students (admitted through the regular interview process), not granted another externally sponsored fellowship (e.g., TCS, Qualcomm, TI, Intel, Visvesvaraya, WIRIN, etc.), are eligible to apply.</p> <p>The evaluation committee will look at the applicant’s academic profile, proposed and past contributions to CNI activities, and the relevance of the proposed research to the centre’s objective of showcasing innovative applications or theories of networked intelligence. Higher relevance will be assigned to proposed work in the current CNI project topics:</p> <ul> <li>Data center networks</li> <li>Data-driven decision frameworks for public health</li> <li>Deterministic networks and programmable data plane</li> <li>Industrial control systems</li> <li>Wi-Fi optimisation and network slicing</li> </ul> <h3 id="monthly-fellowship-support">Monthly fellowship support:</h3> <p>The CNI fellows will be selected by the evaluation committee, and the CNI scholarship will be in lieu of the MoE scholarship. Exact amount will be indicated at the time of award, and a selected few fellows will receive a slightly higher monthly remuneration.</p> <h3 id="additional-benefits">Additional benefits:</h3> <p>CNI also offers financial support for research publications and conference travel (up to Rs 2 lakh of which 50% can be used for funding of international travel) subject to availability of funds.</p> <p>Additional honorarium will be paid to the fellows assisting in conducting CNI events. CNI fellows are expected to actively participate in CNI events and contribute towards CNI activities during the year.</p> <h3 id="application-process">Application process:</h3> <p>Following information should be included in the fellowship application:</p> <ol> <li>Covering letter indicating how your wor relates to networked intelligence systems and the Centre’s areas of interest. Please indicate how you propose to contribute to CNI activities such as network seminar series organisation or online course modules (mention the course topics).</li> <li>Full academic résumé including marks/grades in Bachelors, Masters, other degrees, years of graduation, honours and awards, publications, work experience, etc.</li> <li>IISc course transcript.</li> <li>A two-page write-up on your research area — include a short review, broad problem statement, proposed scope, and focus. Please include any results already obtained and the papers published.</li> </ol> <p>The application <strong>email</strong> with a single PDF document as attachment (size at most 10 MB) needs to be forwarded by adviser and should reach contact.cni@iisc.ac.in <strong>on or before <del>16-Aug-2022</del> 21-Aug-2022 (IST).</strong></p> <p>More details on past CNI fellowships are at <a href="https://cni.iisc.ac.in">https://cni.iisc.ac.in</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for applications: CNI PhD Fellowship (2022-23)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">CNI Summer School 2022</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/summer-school-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNI Summer School 2022"/><published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/Summer_School</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/summer-school-2022/"><![CDATA[<p>The 2022 edition of CNI Summer school is here!</p> <p><img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/images/posts/SummerSchool2022_poster.png" alt=""/></p> <p>This year’s summer school will be in the form of a short course on Online Algorithms, taught by Prof. Rahul Vaze from TIFR Mumbai. It will be conducted in hybrid mode (online as well as in-person participation in IISc Campus).</p> <h2 id="details">Details</h2> <p>For many optimization problems of interest, the input instance is revealed sequentially, and an algorithm has to execute/make irrevocable decisions sequentially with partially revealed input, amid uncertainty about the future input. This sequential decision setting is generally referred to as the online setting, and the corresponding algorithm as an online algorithm.</p> <p>In this series of five lectures, we will cover five basic online decision problems, that are also well motivated from applications. Through these five problems, we will highlight some important analytical techniques such as the potential function method, primal-dual schema, Yao’s principle etc.</p> <h3 id="schedule">Schedule</h3> <p><strong>Dates: May 02-06</strong><br/> <strong>Duration:</strong> Five sessions of approx. 2 hours each<br/> <strong>Timings: Mornings 10am to 11:50am</strong> (with one short break in between).<br/></p> <h2 id="target-audience-and-registration">Target audience and registration</h2> <p>The Summer School is targeted at 4th Year Bachelors’/dual-degree students or Masters’/PhD students in engineering (ECE/CS/EE or related streams). A (free) registration is required for participation in the Summer School.</p> <p>We have a limited seats available for those who are keen to attend the sessions in IISc campus in-person. Please express your intent for in-person sessions only if you are sure about attending all sessions in IISc and we’ll confirm (over email) if we can accommodate you for offline (in-person) participation. Please note that IISc will not be providing any travel/food/stay assistance for those attending in-person sessions.</p> <p>For participating in online mode, <a href="https://thingqbator.nasscomfoundation.org/main/eventdetail/6255754bcc00986bcbb1563f">please register</a>. We have partnered with ThingQBator (NASSCOM Foundation) for the hosting of online mode this year.</p> <p>If you are keen on attending summer school in-person (limited number of slots available) at IISc campus, please express your interest by <a href="https://forms.gle/UDqqxHFTWLfzh9Yu5">filling up the form</a>.</p> <p>Please email us at contact.cni@iisc.ac.in in case of difficulties in registering or for more details.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2022 edition of CNI Summer school is here!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CNI joins hands with IIT Madras, Indian Statistical Institute, and Semantic Web India to continue COVID-19 Data Website Operations</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/CNI-COVID/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNI joins hands with IIT Madras, Indian Statistical Institute, and Semantic Web India to continue COVID-19 Data Website Operations"/><published>2021-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/CNI_COVID</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/CNI-COVID/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Among the latest in <a href="https://cni.iisc.ac.in/covid-19-response/">CNI’s contributions towards COVID-19 response</a>,</em> <a href="https://www.iitm.ac.in/">Indian Institute of Technology Madras</a>, the <a href="https://www.iitm.ac.in/">Centre for Networked Intelligence</a> at the <a href="https://iisc.ac.in/">Indian Institute of Science (IISc)</a> and the <a href="https://www.isical.ac.in/">Indian Statistical Institute</a> (ISI) are collaborating with <a href="http://www.semanticwebindia.com/index.html#extHeader5-6i">Semantic Web</a> India, a private technology firm based in Bangalore, to continue the efforts of a critical COVID-19 Data Website.</p> <p><img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/images/posts/screenshot-2021-11-24-213945-1536x768.png" alt=""/></p> <p><a href="https://www.covid19india.org">www.covid19india.org</a> offered a comprehensive view on the pandemic across India by providing data on confirmed cases, active and recovered cases, tests and fatalities. The portal also recently started showing vaccination administration status for single-dose and fully vaccinated.</p> <p>The website, which till now was run by volunteers based on a crowd-sourcing model, provided valuable data to the public as well as researchers studying the pandemic. <strong>The organisers recently announced that they would stop their operations beyond 31st October 2021.</strong></p> <p><img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/images/posts/screenshot-2021-11-24-214123.png" alt=""/></p> <p><strong>This new initiative of these Academic Institutions and Semantic Web India will now continue updating the data from 1st November 2021 and make it available at <a href="www.incovid19.org">www.incovid19.org</a>.</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among the latest in CNI’s contributions towards COVID-19 response, Indian Institute of Technology Madras, the Centre for Networked Intelligence at the Indian Institute of Science (IISc) and the Indian Statistical Institute (ISI) are collaborating with Semantic Web India, a private technology firm based in Bangalore, to continue the efforts of a critical COVID-19 Data Website.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AADHAAR Hackathon 2021</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/announcing-hackathon-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AADHAAR Hackathon 2021"/><published>2021-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/AADHAR_Hackathon_2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/announcing-hackathon-2021/"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce the Aadhaar Hackathon 2021, in partnership with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).</p> <p>The hackathon, featuring unique challenges to solve regarding authentication and data registry update, is open to all engineering students in India. There are bountiful prizes to be won, too!</p> <p>Please head over to <a href="https://hackathon.uidai.gov.in/">https://hackathon.uidai.gov.in</a> for more details. <img src="https://alshedivat.github.io/cni_new/images/posts/aadhar_hackathon.jpeg" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="event"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the Aadhaar Hackathon 2021, in partnership with the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI).]]></summary></entry></feed>